Charlotte Bush

Brooklyn, NY | 202-441-7231 | clangbush@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charlottebush7/ | https://github.com/Varlotte | https://dev.to/varlotte | https://femmefaust.us/dev

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Junior developer experienced in Python with Flask and JavaScript-based programming and a background in innovative learning experience design. Possesses strong skills in communication and managing projects and people to support company-wide goals. Award-winning off-off Broadway playwright and producer, and writer on triple-A video games.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Flask, SQL, JavaScript, React, YAML, Flask-SQLalchemy, HTML and CSS, Wordpress, Confluence, Jira, Edmodo, Articulate360, Udemy, Blackboard, Final Cut Pro, Notion, Greenhouse, Zendesk, Salesforce, Tableau

RECENT TECHNICAL PROJECTS

RXGnosis - Github- https://rxgnosis.com/

RXGnosis is a patient advocacy app to research and save a list of medications before doctor's appointments.

- Created a full-stack application guided by user stories to make reliable treatment data accessible for patients.
- Converted peer-reviewed federal data on 16 medications and 4 conditions into YAML seed data on the backend.
- Used Chakra component library to ensure coherent and ARIA-compliant styling throughout the app.
- Refactored the backend for security, adding Node, Vite, Postgres, Prisma, Firebase, Superstruct and middleware.
- Deployed to production on Vercel, currently in beta testing.

FemmeFaust.us - Github - https://femmefaust.us/dev

Femmefaust.us is a single-page React app portfolio site displaying my artistic and technological projects.

- Refactored the website from Svelte SPA into React SPA, including switching from JavaScript to TypeScript and adding Vite and Vanilla Extract.
- Added Developer portfolio page, including building an embed for Dev.to blog.
- Deployed to production on Surge.

SELECTED EXPERIENCE

Care.comBrooklyn, NYContent and Process Specialist2022-2022

Managed cross-departmental learning and development (L&D) initiatives meet learning goals across a 500 person organization

- Led a cross-functional team to address new hire attrition, including data collection, project scoping, redesigning eLearning for onboarding and management best practices, and talent acquisition, affecting 200+ global employees
- Led a cross-functional team to address DEIB recruiting strategies. Created 12+ hours of new eLearning multimedia for this initiative
- Formed a new employee resource group for neurodiverse staff, affecting 50+ employees

JustworksBrooklyn, NYOnboarding Manager2021-2022

Managed all aspects of a seamless onboarding onto the Justworks professional employer organization (PEO) platform for 50+ executives

- Successfully applied knowledge of instructional design to facilitate and enhance each business' month-long virtual onboarding experience while serving as the primary administrative point of contact
- Facilitated data-driven People Operations optimization support for small business and HR stakeholders

HYPOTHEkidsBrooklyn, NYProgram Manager2021-2021

Developed and piloted STEAM curricula, training, resources, and programming for underserved NYC young people

- Created and delivered STEAM programming for 2,000+ children, including recruiting, training, and management of 20+ teachers
- Took ownership of HRIS and LMS tools to lead online and hybrid professional development for staff in 12 partner institutions

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Brooklyn, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program 07/2023 - 11/2023

CUNY Hunter College

New York, NY
Master's of Science, Special Education

06/2017

University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA
Bachelor's of Arts, Medieval Studies 06/2012